Guide to the Leon Kolb collection of Portraits: engravings, etchings, mezzotinits, lithographs, and acquatints, M0871
Stanford University. Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 1. Accn 1972-002, 12.0 Linear feet 1647 items (prints)
  - 1424. Sunderland, Henry Spencer, 1st earl of, 17th cent. (Flat-box 11, Folder 14)
    Henry Spencer, First Earl of Sunderland./From the original of Walker, in the Collection of/The Right Hon.ble The Earl Spencer/Drawn by R.W.Satchwell & Engraved (with Parmission) by R.Cooper. /London Published Fab.r 1.1817. by Lackington, Allen & Co. and Longman, Hurst, Rees, Orme & Brown. Knee-piece in oblong looking left. Stipple-engraving. 36.4 x 25.8 cm, Plate-mark partly trimmed off.
  - 1425. Sunderland, Robert Spencer, 2nd earl of, 1640-1702 (Flat-box 11, Folder 14)
    Robert Spencer, Earl of Sunderland/From the original of Carlo Maratta in the Collection of/The Right Hon.ble The Earl Spencar./Drawn by R,W.Satchwell & Engraved (with Permission) by R. Cooper./London. Published June 1, 1817. by Lackington, Hughes, Harding, Maven & Jones and Longnan, Hurst, Rees, Orme & Brown. Knee-piece in oblong looking left. Stipple-engraving. 36.4 x 25.8 cm. Plate-mark partly trimmed off.
  - 1426. Surrey, Henry Howard, earl of, 1517?-1547 (Flat-box 11, Folder 14)
    Henry Howard, Earl of Surrey./J.Houbnaken sculps. Aunst./Impensis J. & P.Knapton Londini, 1750. Bust in lettered oval looking slightly left surrounded by Baroque decoration. Engraving. 36.9 x 23.3 cm. From: Birch, T., The Heads of the Most Illustrious Persons of. Great Britain, J.Knapton, London, 1756.
  - 1427. Sussex, Anne Wake, ?-1680 (Flat-box 11, Folder 14)
    D,Anna Wake./Ant. van Dyck pinxit. Petrus Clouwet sculpsit. Knee-piece in oblong looking left. Engraving. 225.9 x 18.5 cm Singer No. 30304/88719. Dutuit No. l79.3e. Mauquoy-H. No. l71.V. Plate-mark trimmed off. From: Iconographyof Vandyke.
  - 1428. Sutherland, George Granville Sutherland-Leveson-Gowar, 2nd Duke of, 1786-1861
    Item missing. George Granville, Marquess ofStrafford, K.G./Engraved from a Picture by Thomas Phil-lips Esqr. R.A. by John Young Engraver of His Majesty./London. Nov.15.l829. Published by the Engraver, Upper Charlton Street. Bust in oblong looking left. Mezzotint. 29.3 x 23.6 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark.
  - 1429. Swalm, Eleazor, 1582-1652 (Flat-box 11, Folder 14)
    Aldus dnaacht Swalmius aen scroon van grauwe haren,/Geborem uit de zorg van vystich mmvian janen/Die by aant karke-roer als grauwe stienman staat,/Die by met balder licht hat yolk heast voorgatradem/In deucht en wetenschap en aangename reden,/En yacht tot dat de Hear hem van zyn wacht onstlaat./Rambrant pinxit: I.Suijdenhoef sculpsit.. P.Goos axcudit. H.Geldorpius. Seated knee-piece in oblong looking left. Engraving. 33.0 x 26.1 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off.Singer No. 30342/88795.
  - 1430. Swedenborg, Emanuel, 1688-1772 (Flat-box 11, Folder 14)
    Emanuel Swedenb org. /Ch. Graf s cuip. Bust in oval facing viewer. Stipple-engraving. 16.5 x 10.0 cm, Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 1431. Swedenborg, Emanuel, 1688-1772 (Flat-box 11, Folder 15)
    Swedenborg,/Painted by Martin. Engraved by J.Andrews and pupil./Entered according to Act of Congress in the Year 1854 by Otis Clapp in the Clerk's Office of the District Court of Massachusetts./Enterad at Stationer's Hall. Photo-engraving. 29.8 x 22.8 cm.
  - 1432. Symons, Ralph, 1583-1603 (Flat-box 11, Folder 15)
    Ralph Simons, Architect/From an original Picture which was in the possession of the late Mr.Essex at Cambnidge./Th.Kerrich del. Engraved by Facius. Bust in oblong looking right. Stipple-engraving. 17.7 x 12.2 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 1433. Erratum: The numbers, not entries, 1433 and 1434, were inadvertantly omitted.
    Item missing. Aristocrat, English. W. Dorothy Sidney, Countess of Sunderland./From the original of Vandyke, in the Collec- tion of The Right Hon.ble The Earl of Egremont./Drawn by R.W.Satchwell & Engraved (with Permission) by W.T.Fny./London. Published Oct.r, 31.1816. by Lackington, Allen & Co. and Longman, Hurst, Rees, Orme & Brown. Knee-piece in oblong looking left. Stipple-engraving. 36.4 x 25.8 cm. Plate-mark partly trimmed off.
  - 1434. Erratum: The numbers, not entries, 1433 and 1434, were inadvertantly omitted.
  - 1435. Taje, van Wemmel, Engelbert, 17th cent. (Flat-box 11, Folder 15)
    Dominus Engelbertus Taie Eques, Bare Wenmelius Etc.a/Deputatus Ordinarius Inter No-biles Status Brabantiae./Amtonius van Dyck pinxit. Cornelius Galle uinior sculpsit. excudit Antverpiae. Half-portrait in oblong looking left. Engraving. 25.8 x 18.7 cm. Singer No, 30468/89057, Dutuit No. 130.2e. Mauquoy-H. No. 128.11. Trimmed close to plate-mark. From: Iconography of Vandyke.
  - 1436. Talleyrand-Perigord, Charles Maurice de, prince de Benevent, 1754-1838 (Flat-box 11, Folder 15)
    Ch.Mau.Pce de Talleyrand/nd a Paris le 2 fdvrier l754./V.Vogel delt./London.26 Iunii 1834,/Luth. Amst.v.Pobuda Rees at Cie. Bust looking slightly left. Lithograph. 18.7 x 15.4 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark. Singer No. 30479/89079.
  - 1437. Talleyrand-Perigord, Charles Maurice de, prince de Benevent, 1754-1838 (Flat-box 11, Folder 15)
    Charles Maurice/Prince de Talleyrand./Engraved by T.Hodgetts from the Original Picture by A.Scheffer in the Collection of/the Right Hon.ble Henry Richard Vassall Fox. Lord Holland & Baron Foxlay etc./London 1835 Published by Messrs Colnaghi & Co. print- sellers in Ordinary to the King & Co H.R.H. the Duchess of Kent./No 23 Cockspur Street. Charing Cross./Deposd a la direction. Se vend a Paris chez M.Pieri Bernard Boulevard des Italiems No. 11. Knee-piece in oblong looking right. Mezzotint. 42.7 x 29.5 cue.
  - 1438. Tanner, Thomas, bp. of Alaph, 1674-1735 (Flat-box 11, Folder 15)
    Reverendus admodum/Thomas Tanner, Alaphemsis Episcopus/Primoevae Antiquitatis Cultor. G.Vertue Sculp. 1743. Bust in oval looking right over symbolic composition of scrolls and books; some having "Lelan" and "Notuita monastica" on edge or spine. Engraving. 30,5 x 17.7 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark.
  - 1439. Tasso, Torquato, 1544-1595 (Flat-box 11, Folder 15)
    Torquato Tasso./Milano presso lo Stampatore Giovanni Cogliati./Jacopo Bernardi incise. Raff, Morghen diresse. Bust in oblong looking left. Stipple-engraving. 23.1 x 16.4 cm.
  - 1440. Taxis [Tassis], Anthonis de, ?-1651 (Flat-box 11, Folder 15)
    Antonius de Tassis./Canonicus Antverpianus Picturaa Statuariae./Nac Non Omnis Elegantiae Anator Et Admirator./Ant.van Dyck pinxit. lacobus Neeffs scuipsit. Knee-piece in oblong looking slightly left. Engraving. 26.3 x 18.7 cm. Singer No. 30596/89364. Dutuit No. ll6.4e. Mauquoy-H. No. 1l4.IV. From: Iconography of Vandyke.
  - 1441. Taylor, Dan, 1738-1816 (Flat-box 12, Folder 1)
    A Fawning Flatterer Dan Taylor/Thou sea'st not what thou see'st, then doe not say/ That this is Hee: who calls a lump of clay/Without the Soul a Man? Thou seest no Mora,/ Nay but the shadow of that lump what store/Of guifts and graces what perfections rare/ Among 10 000 Persons scatter'd are/Gather in One; Imagine it to bee/His Shadowses sub- stance And then say 'tis hee/ A down-right Dealer I: Vicars/ I shame to sea, what (beer) I see, and say/That this is Hee, who fast and loose doth play/With Piety. A Soul full of Deceipt/Closd in a Lump of Clay the World to cheat/In whom the Scatter'd Boyles of Errors base/Of full 10 000 Sectarias take place/Gath'rad in One. And thus if thou wilt see/Heresies substance, in a shade tis Hee. Half-portrait between emblematic composition (with verbal decoration) looking left, Engraving. 12.0 x 14.0 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 1442. Taylor, Jeremy, 1613-1667 (Flat-box 12, Folder 1)
    [Jerome Taylor] B.Lombart sculpsit./Non magna loquimur sad viv~mus/nihi1 opinionis gratia omnia/conscentiae faciam. Half-portrait in oval looking right. Engraving. 25.7 x 14.8 cm, Plate-mark trimmed off, Singer No, 30615/89398.
  - 1443. Taylor, John, 1694-1761 (Flat-box 12, Folder 1)
    Johannes Taylor, Lancastria Oriundus, Et Numc Apud Norvicenses Rerum Laetarum Praeco. Anno 1754./Hems pinx. 1746. J.Houbraken sculp. 1754. Bust in lettered oval looking left. Book with "Biblia" on spine, map with "Iter Paulinum" on it in allegory below portrait. Engraving. 35.0 x 21.8 cm.
  - 1444. Teissier, Eustache, 17th cent. (Flat-box 12, Folder 1)
    D.Eustachius Teissier Generalis Toti Ordinis SS.Trinitatis et Redemptionis Captivorum./P.vanschuppen sculp. et ex. C.P.R. l690./Offerebat Addictissin P.Rob.Hard.Mey Be Valombre Paris. Relig. Eiusd. Ord. Bust in lettered oval facing viewer. Engraving. 36.8 x 30.7 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark.
  - 1445. Temple, Sir William, 1628-1699 (Flat-box 12, Folder 1)
    Sr William Temple./In the Collection of John Temple Esqr/P.Lely pinxit. J.Houbraken sculps. Amst./Impensis J. & P.Knapton. Londini, 1738. Bust in lettered oval looking left, surrounded by symbolic Baroque composition. Engraving. 37.2 x 23.7 cm. Singer No. 30674/89525. From: Birch, T., The Heads ~ the ~o!S~~ Illustrious Perspns of Great Britain~ J.Knapton, London, 1743.
  - 1446. Teniers, David the Younger, 1610-1690 (Flat-box 12, Folder 1)
    David Teniers./Un tres excellent peintre en petite figures et paijsages, il a faict de remarquables/pieces tant pour le Roy d'Espaigne.que pour autres Roys, de mesme pour l'Archiduc Leopold Guilleaume, l'Evesque de Gand, et le Prince d'Orange Guillane et/ plusieurs autres Princes, Seigneurs et Amateurs de l'art ont beaucoup de ses oeuvres,/il est me d'Anvers 1 an 1610. ayant eu son pere pour maistre./Dav. Teniers pinxit. Pet.de lode sculpsit. Io.Meyssens excudit. Bust in oblong looking slightly left. Engraving. 16.7 x 11.5 cm. Prom: Meyssens, J., The true Effigies of the mot eminent Painters... that have flourished in Europe... Engraven, [Anvers], 1694.
  - 1447. Thevenot, Melchisedeck, 1620-1692 (Flat-box 12, Folder 1)
    Monsieur de Thevenot./W.Paithorne Sc. Full figure looking right in oblong. Engraving. 25.1 x 14.6 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 1448. Thomassin, da St.Paul Louis, 1619-1695 (Flat-box 12, Folder 1)
    Louis Thomassim./Prestra da l'Oratoira./Jacobus Van Schuppen ad vivum pinxit. P.Van Schuppan Sculpsit. C.P.R. 1696. Bust in oval looking right. Engraving. 25.7 a 18.8 cm.
  - 1449. Thou, Augustin, ?-1544 (Flat-box 12, Folder 1)
    La Président de Thou./Jac,Lubin Sculp. Bust in oval looking left. Engraving. 25.6 19.5 cm.
  - 1450. Throckmorton, Sir Nicholas, ?-1570 (Flat-box 12, Folder 1)
    Sr. Nicholas Throckmorton Kt./Ob,t 1570./Ha Tabula Antqua. G.Vartue del. at sculp. 1747. Bust in oval looking left in symbolic composition. Engraving. 36.7 a 23.7 cm.
  - 1451. Thumbshirn, Wolfgang Konrad, ?-1667 (Flat-box 12, Folder 2)
    Wolfgang Conradus a Thumbshirn in Ponia./Cessissimi at Ilustrissimi Principis ac Domini Dni Friderici/Wilhelmi Saxoniaa, Juliae, Cliviaa at Montium Ducis/Consiliarius Aulicus, Aararij Privincialis Director at/Consistorij Assessor atq. ad Tractatus Pacis Uni -versalis/Legatus Plemipotentiarius./Anselmus van Hulle pinait. Corn.Galla iunior sculp./ 1649. Accassit Privilegium Caesaraum./Cum privilegio Regum at Hollandiae ordinum. Bust looking left in oval lettered: "Recta agando naminam timeas." Engraving. 30.6 a 19.8 cm, No. 84 from: Hulla, A. van, Pacificatores orbis Christiani..,Rotterdam, 1697.
  - 1452. Thurlow, John, 1619-1684 (Flat-box 12, Folder 2)
    John Thurlow Secretary to Oliver Cromwell./In the collection of th~ Lord James Cavandish./J.Houbrakan sculps./Cooper pinx.flmpensis J. & P.Knapton, London 1738. Bust in lettered oval looking right surrounded by symbolic Baroque composition. Engraving. 35.5 a 22.5 cm. Singer No. 30998/90398. From: Birch, T., The Heads of the Most Illustrious Persons of Great Britain, J.Knapton, London, 1743.
  - 1453. Thurloe, John, 1619-1684 (Flat-box 12, Folder 2)
    John Thurloa./Author of State Papers ,/Obit, 1668. From a drawing ~ ~ huilfinch of the original picture./London. Published by S.Woodburn, 1813, R.Dunkarton u pt. Bust in oblong looking right. Mezzotint. 28.9 x 20.8 cm.
  - 1454. Tiberius, Claudius Nero, 3rd emperor of Rome, 42 B.C.-37 A.D. (Flat-box 12, Folder 2)
    Tiberius Caasar./Titiamus inventor. Aegidius Sadeler excud.[])ouble qua ra.c nder picture.]No. III. Half-portrait in oblong looking left. Engraving. 25.5 x 24.3 cm.
  - 1455. Tibarius, Claudius Nero, 3rd emperor of Rome, 42 B.C.-37 A.D. (Flat-box 12, Folder 2)
    Imp. Ti. Caesar. Divi. Aug. F. Augustus III. Right profile in lettered circle. Over portrait: ‘Als ich todt se~ \erm_scile 5ach das arttraich mitt/den fewerr.” Under portrait: "Nach dam er alt war ‘B. or. mid 2~ am Reich/gessassen, ist im mit gifft das leben ganommen.” Engraving. 23.8 x 20.7 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark. No. 3 from an unidentified German version of Suatonius T., VitaXdesaruii
  - 1456. Tiberius, Claudius Nero, 3rd emperor of Rome, 42 B.C.-37 A.D. (Flat-box 12, Folder 2)
    Tiberius/born at Rome, reigned/ 2Oyears, 5 Months, 28 Days,/died in t~e ~as of Corist:37. Left profile in oval lettered: "Ti Caesar. Divi. Aug. F. Aug. lisp. Engraving. 18.2 x 10.5 cm. Plate-mark partly trimmed off. Illustration: Vol. XIV. page 46.” from unidentified book.
  - 1457. Tibarius, Claudius Nero, 3rd emperor of Rome, 42 B.C.-37 A.D. (Flat-box 12, Folder 2)
    Tibarius, Caesar./C.Tibara Cesar, Fils da Tibera quastaur souz Jul Ces, a Is Civic Drusile sa famme. Depuis mariée a l’Emp./Augusta. qui l’adopta a l’Emp, fut is Is imps-reur Romain. Il regna 23 ans,. .Son Napueu Caligula le fit ampoisonner. Jesus Christ flu: crucifié l’an l5e de l’Emp. da Tibere./Suat./P.Mariette excudit III Bust in oblong looking right. Engraving. 28,4 a 19.4 cm, Trimmed close to plate-mark. No. 3 from an unidentified edition of: Suetonius, T., Histoiredes couzeflfisars.
  - 1458. Tillamans, Peter, 1684-1734 (Flat-box 12, Folder 2)
    Peter Tillamans./Hissings pinait. T.Chambars Sculp. Half-portrait in oblong looking right. Engraving. 17.1 a 13.0 cm
  - 1459. Tillotson, John, abp. of Canterbury, 1630-1694 (Flat-box 12, Folder 2)
    Revarendissimus in Chnisto Patar Johannas Tillotson Providentia Divina/Archiapis- copus Cantuaniensis totius Angliae Primas at Metrapolitanus Sara/nissimis Pnincipibus Regi Guglialmo at Reginaa Maniae a Secratioribus consoliys, R.White delis at sculp. Bust in oval wreath looking right. Engraving. 28.2 x 18.8 cm.
  - 1460. Tillotson, John, abp. of Canterbury, 1630-1694 (Flat-box 12, Folder 2)
    The most Reverend! Dr John Tillotson/lata Arch-Bishop of Cantarbury./R.Whita sculp. Bust in oval looking right. Engraving. 15.8 x 10.1 cm, Plate-mark partly trimmed off.
  - 1461. Tillotsom, John, abp. of Canterbury, 1630-1694 (Flat-box 12, Folder 3)
    Tillotson, Arch Bishop of Canterbury./In the Collection of the Right Hon. the Master of the Rolls./G.Knaller pina. Jacobus Houbraken sculps. Amst. Bust in lettered oval looking right surrounded by symbolic Baroque composition. Engraving. 36.0 x 22.7 cm. Singer No. 31066/90655. From: Birch, T., The Heads of the Most Illustrious Per~pp~~pf Great Britain, J.Knapton, London, 1756.
  - 1462. Tilly, Johann Tserclaes, 1559-1632 (Flat-box 12, Folder 3)
    Illust.mus loanmes. Com. Da. Tserclaas. Dom. Tilli. Baro./De Morbays Don. De. Ballast Etc./Pet. de loden sculp. Ant. van Dyck pinxit. Cum privilegio. Half-portrait in oblong looking right. Engraving. 23.9 a 18.3 cm. Singer No. 31068/90664. Dutuit No. 37.4a. Mauquoy-H. No. 30.IV. From: Iconography of Vandyke.
  - 1463. Tilson, Henry, 1659-1695 (Flat-box 12, Folder 3)
    Henry Tilson./Ipsa pinx. T.Chambars sculp. Bust in oblong looking left. Stipple-engraving. 16.8 x 13.2 cm.
  - 1464. Timmerscheidt, Johann, 17th cent. (Flat-box 12, Folder 3)
    Joannes Timmerscheidt. I.V.L.tus/Conclusae at publicatae Pacis tempore/Consul Civita tis Nonasteniansis./Anselmus van Hulle pinait. Matthaaus Borrekens sculpsit 1649. Cum pnivilegio Ragum at Hollandiae, Accassit Privilegium Caesaneum ordinum. Bust looking left in oval lettarad:"Aaquam memento rebus in arduis servare mentem." Engraving. 30.6 x 19.8 cm. No. 126 from: Hulle, A. van, Pacificatoras prbis Christiani, Rottardam, 1697. Singer No. 31074/90712.
  - 1465. Tindal, Matthew, 1653?-1733 (Flat-box 12, Folder 3)
    Matthew Tindall L.L.D. Aatat. 78./Heu Pnisca Fidas./B.Dandnidge Pina. 1733. I.Faber fecit./Sold by J.Faben at the Golden Head ye. South side of Bloomsbury Square. Bust in oblong looking left. Mezzotint. 34.8 x 25.3 cm. Singer No. 31077/90718.
  - 1466. Tindal, Nicholas, 1687-1774 (Flat-box 12, Folder 3)
    Nicolas Tindal./G.Knapton pinait. B.Picart sculp. 1733. Bust in oval looking right. Engraving.32.7 x 22.0 cm. Singer No. 31078/90719.
  - 1467. Titus Flavius Sabinus Vaspasianus, 11th emperor of Rome, 41-81 A.D.
    Item missing. Imp. T./Caes. Vasp. Aug. P.M.Tr.P.P. Cos.VIII IX. Right profile in lettered circle. Engraving. 24.1 x 20.7 cm, Trimmed close to plate-mark. No.11 from unidentified German version of Suetonius, T., Vita XII.Caasarum
  - 1468. Tiziano, Vecelli, 1477-1576 (Flat-box 12, Folder 3)
    La Titiam./ La Titian pinxit. La tableau original appartient a M.Chaix d’Est-Ange, 1842 Alp Francois sculp. Publié a Paris par H.Gache editeur, 58 Rue de la Victoire, Imp. par Chardon Ainé at Axe. Bust looking left, Photo-engraving. 41.0 x 30,9 cm.
  - 1469. Todenwart, Johann Jakob-Wolfgang, 1585-1657 (Flat-box 12, Folder 3)
    Joan Jakob Wolff a Todenwarth./Calsissimi Pnincipis at Domini Gaorgii/Landgravij Hassiaa-Darmstad: ut at laudatiss. Raipub. Ratisponensis Consilianius,et/ad Tractatus Pads Generalis Lagatus./accessit pnivilagium Caasareum Ansalmus van Hulla pinait. Corn. Galla scuipsit. Cum pnivilegio Regun at Hollandiaa ordinum 1649. Bust looking left in oval lettered: "Sperandum at ferendum." Engraving. 30.5 x 19.5 cm. Singer No. 31119/90807. No. 96 from: Pacificatores orbis Chnistiani...,Rotterdam, 1697.
  - 1470. Tollenache, Thomas, 1615?-1694 (Flat-box 12, Folder 3)
    Lieutenant General Talmash./In the Collection of the Right Hon: the Earl of Dysant./ G,Knellar pinx. J,Houbraken sculpsit. Bust in lettered oval looking left in symbolic Baroque composition, Engraving. 36.9 a 23.1 cm. Singer No. 31151/90873. From: Birch, T., TheHeadsoftheMost Illustrious Persons of Great Britain, J.Knapton, London, 1756.
  - 1471. Torrington, George, 1633-1733 (Flat-box 12, Folder 4)
    George Byng Lord Tornington./In the Collection of the Right lion. the Lord Visc. Tarningtom./G.Kneller pinait. J.Houbraken sculps. Anst. 1747./Iinpensis J. & P. Knapton, Lomdini, 1747. Bust in lettered oval looking slightly left, surrounded by symbolic Baroque composition, Engraving. 36.2 a 21.3 cm. From: Birch, T., The Heads of the Most Illustrious Persons of Great Britain, J.Knapton, London, 1747.
  - 1472. Totnes, George Carew, earl of, 1555-1629 (Flat-box 12, Folder 4)
    George Carew, Earl of Totnes./From the original of Zuccheno in the Collection of/The Right Hon.bla The Earl of Nerulam./Drawm by R.W.Satchwell & Engraved (with Permission) by H.Meyar./London. Published July 1.1817 by Lackington, Hughes, Harding, Mayor & Jonas and Longman, Hurst, Rees, Orma, & Brown. Knee-piece in oblong looking right. Stipple-engraving. 36.4 a 25.8 cm. Plate-mark partly trimmed off. a, Zuccani, Fedenico, 1540-1609. Italian.
  - 1473. Towgood, Micaiah, 1700-1792 (Flat-box 12, Folder 4)
    The Rev,Micaiah Towgood/From a Painting in the Possession of the Rev. J.Manning./ Painted by J.Opie Esq. R.A. Engraved by E.A,Ezekiel./Exeter: Published March lst.1794, by E.A.Ezekiel. Engraver, Fore Street. Knee-piece in oblong facing viewer. Mezzotint, 57.0 x 34.5 cm.
  - 1474. Trajanus, Marcus Ulpius, 14th emperor of Rome, 53-117 A.D. (Flat-box 12, Folder 4)
    Traianus Imp./l2. Right profile in oblong. Engraving. 18.5 x 15.0 cm, Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 1475. Trandorf, August Adolph, 17th cent. (Flat-box 12, Folder 4)
    Augustus Adophus Baro de Trantorf/Sarenissimi Electonis Saxoniae Generalis Vigilum/ nec non Legionis Pedestris Praafectus Ejusdemq/ad Tractatum Nonimbergensem Executionis Pacis/Germaniae Legatus./Anselmus van Hulle pinxit./Petrus da lode sculp. Accessit Pni- vilegium Caesareum. Cum privilagio Regum at Hollandiae ordinum. Bust looking left in oval lettered: "Tampore cum omnia." Engraving. 30.2 a 20.0 cm. No, 73 from unidentified edition of: Hulle, A.van, Pacificatores orbis Chnistiani.
  - 1476. Trappen [Bankert], Joos van, ?-1646 (Flat-box 12, Folder 4)
    Adriaan Bankent,/Lt.Adminal van Zaeland./A.Schouman del, naar de Onig.Schildery by den Hr.Parker te Middalbumg. J.Houbraken fec. Is.Tinion eacud. 1760. Bust in oval looking left framed by oblong. Engraving. 18.2 a 11.8 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off
  - 1477. Trauttmannsdorf, Maximilian, count da, 1584-1650 (Flat-box 12, Folder 4)
    Maximilianus Comes de Trautmanstorff et Wainsbarg./Baro in Glaichanberg, Neostadij ad Kochenam Nagau Burgau et/Totzanbach Dffs in Teimites at Leithomisch. Eques Auras Val- lens Sacnaa/Caes.Mtis Consiliarius Intimus Cubiculanius Supremis Auiae Praefectus/Cas- talli Gretziensis Capitaneus, atque ad Tractatus Pacis Univer/salis tam Monastenij,quam Osnabrugi, aiusdem suae Caasa.Mtis/Nomina Lagatus Plenipotentiarius Pnimarius. /Arisalmus van Hulle pinait. Patrus da Jade sculpsit./1648./Accessit Pnivilegium Caesareum. Cum Pni- vilegio Regum at Hollamdiae ordinum. Bust looking left in oval lettered: "Aetamna in desiderio sint temporalia in usu,' Engraving. 31.5 x 20.3 cm. Singer No. 31282/91182. No. 39 from: Hulla, A.van, Celaberrirni ad pacificamdurn Chris tiani nominus orbem D. Middelar, Anvers, 1648.
  - 1478. Trabonianus, Gallus, 30th emperor of Rome, 205-254 A.D. (Flat-box 12, Folder 4)
    The Emperor Trebonianus Gallus./P.Dujardin ang. Gebbie & Co. Unframad sculpture-bust facing viewer. Lithograph. 36,5 a 26.7 cm, Torn from book.
  - 1479. Triast, Anthomis, 7th bp. of Ghemt, 1576-1657 (Flat-box 12, Folder 4)
    Perill.us at Re.mus Dnus D. Antonius Tniest episcopus Gaudavensis/Toparcha Dominy St Bavonis Comes Everghemiensis etc./Ant.van Dyck pinait. Pat.de lode scuip. Cum privilagio. Half-portrait in oblong looking right. Etching. 24.1 x 17.3 cm. Singer No. 31361/91343. Dutuit No. 22.6e. Mauquoy-H. No. l3.X. From: Iconography of Vandyke.
  - 1480. Trigland, Jacob, 1583-1654 (Flat-box 12, Folder 4)
    Jacobus Tnigland./Predicant te Amsterdam Ao, 1610./Professor tot Laydan 1634./VG. pinxit. J.Houbraken sculpsit. Bust in oval looking left. Engraving. 17.6 x 11.7 cm. Trimmed close to plate-mark. Singer No. 31363/91353.
  - 1481. Tromp, Cormelis Silliasburg, count de, 1629-1691 (Flat-box 12, Folder 5)
    Cornalis Tromp./PP.Ordinum Balgij vice prefectus/manis. Bust in oval looking right. Stipple-engraving. 12.4 x 6.8 cm, Badly trimmed.
  - 1482. Tromp, Maerten Harpertsz van, 1597-1653 (Flat-box 12, Folder 5)
    Martinus Herparts Tromp./PP. Ordinum Belgij praafactus/manis. Bust in oblong. Stipple-engraving. 12.3 x 6.8 cm, Badly trimmed.
  - 1483. Troy, Jean Baptiste Francois da, 1679-1752 (Flat-box 12, Folder 5)
    Jean Baptiste François da Tray, Fils/Peintre du Roy, Chevalier de son Ordre/Ancian Recteur da l’Acadëmie, ancian Directaur de calla de France a Roma,/Ancien Prince de celia de St Luc en la m&ne Villa, ou il est mart en Jan.er Feint par Aved, at Grave par N.De Launay. Bust in oval looking right. Engraving. 35.5 a 23.7 cm. Plate-mark trimmed off.
  - 1484. Trumbull, William, 17th cent. (Flat-box 12, Folder 5)
    The Honourabla/William Trumbil Esqr/Envoy to the Court of Brussels/from K.James I. & K.Charlas 1./Ad Exemplar Othonis Vanii D.D.Albartus & Isabella a pictunis Bruxell. l617.facit G,Vartue 1726. Knee-piece in oblong looking right. Engraving. 30.1 a 18.3 cm.
  - 1485. Tulden [van Thuldan], 1600?-1645 (Flat-box 12, Folder 5)